Guide to the Compton Advertising, Inc. Records, 1915-1956 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Compton Advertising, Inc. records 1919-1956 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Compton Advertising, Inc.
2.0 linear feet Extent: 100 Items
Compton Advertising, Inc. was founded in 1937, formed out of the former company Blackman Advertising, Inc. In the 1980s Compton merged with, and was eventually absorbed by, Saatchi & Saatchi. The Compton Advertising, Inc. Records cover the years 1915-1956 and includes proofs of house advertisements and brochures promoting Blackman Advertising, Inc.; its successor Compton Advertising, Inc.; and the Blackett, Sample & Hummert, Inc. agency. Contains an album of mounted photographs; and credentials charts intended for new business presentations. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00251
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Compton Advertising, Inc. Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from O. Milton Gossett in 2003.
Historical Notes
Blackman Company: The Blackman Company was founded by Oscar Blackman and Frank Hermes in 1908, and became known for its 60-year handling of the Procter & Gamble company beginning in the 1920s. In 1935, the company was purchased by its employees Richard Compton (President), Leonard Bush and Alfred Stanford, and two years later was renamed Compton Advertising, Inc. After a period of marked growth during the 1950s and 1960s, Compton merged in 1977 with the Saatchi & Saatchi agency, and was ultimately bought out by that company in 1982. In 1984 Compton was renamed Saatchi, Saatchi & Compton; in 1986, the company was renamed Saatchi & Saatchi.
Blackett-Sample-Hummert: The Blackett-Sample-Hummert Company was founded in 1923 in Chicago. Beginning in the late 1920s, the company became known for its work on behalf of Procter & Gamble soap products, producing daytime radio dramas promoting the products; these became known as soap operas. Some twenty years later, in 1948, the company relocated to New York City, a hub of television broadcasting. The company eventually became known as Dancer Fitzgerald Sample and was purchased by Saatchi & Saatchi for $75 million in 1986. The two companies merged soon after to form the subsidiary company Saatchi & Saatchi DFS Compton.
Collection Overview
The Compton Advertising, Inc. Records cover the years 1915-1956 and includes proofs of house advertisements and brochures promoting Blackman Advertising, Inc.; its successor Compton Advertising, Inc.; and the Blackett, Sample & Hummert, Inc. agency. Contains an album of mounted photographs; and credentials charts intended for new business presentations.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four categories by company name: Blackett, Sample & Hummert, Inc.; Blackman Company; Blackman-Ross Company; and Compton Advertising, Inc. Items were arranged alphabetically by company name and date.
Subject Headings
Compton, Richard J., 1892-1951; Hummert, Frank, 1882-1966; Compton Advertising, Inc.; Blackett-Sample-Hummert, Inc.; Blackman-Ross Company; Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History -- 20th century; House organs; Proofs; Photograph albums; Photographs; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records
O. Milton Gossett Papers
James O'Shaughnessy Papers
Walter Weir Papers
Additional related material may be located in the following collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Advertising Vertical Files
Howard Henderson Papers
Contents of Collection
- Blackett, Sample & Hummert, Inc.
  - Magazine advertisements, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - New business credentials, circa 1936 (Box 1)
  - Photograph album of personnel, circa 1936, (3 folders) (Box 1)
- Blackman Company
  - House advertisements, 1920, 1924-1932, (4 folders) (Box 1)
- Blackman-Ross Company
  - House advertisements appearing in Printer's Ink, 1915-1920, (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Compton Advertising, Inc.
  - Advertisements, 1940-1956 (Box 1)
    [Primarily house advertisements; includes one advertisement for Proctor & Gamble's Duz detergent.]